<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding. Furry. Life.  Coderlion&#39;s blog.</title>
    <description>Coding. Furry. Life.</description>
    <link>http://graemelion.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://graemelion.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Reinvention</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;of-wolves&quot;&gt;Of wolves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there’s this story.  You’ve all heard it before.  It’s about two
wolves, locked in some kind of endless battle.  One of the wolves is
evil, mean, dark.  The other is good, trustful, hopeful.  An outside third party asks, “Which wolf wins?” They get the response: “Whichever one you feed.”  Everyone nods sagely, the message is received, and hopefully the right wolves get fed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then the real world intervenes.  You go about your life.  Someone is wronged.  Someone is slighted.  Hashtags start appearing.  You’re fighting the good fight against &lt;em&gt;evil&lt;/em&gt; and there are many enemies.  You put your head down.  It’s not about wolves anymore, it’s about having to stick up for your friends.  But you have to stick up for them in the right way.  You don’t want to hurt other people.  So you say the words you think are the right words,  and this continues.  Over and over.  You fight, you watch twitter happen, you watch tumblr happen.  Suddenly you wake up one morning and wonder when you turned into such an asshole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You fed the wrong wolf.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wrong-wolf&quot;&gt;The wrong wolf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that helping people is bad.  Standing up for your friends and your beliefs is good.  Doing the right thing is good.  But what’s not good is filling your time with negative things.  You have to be happy too.  You have to let yourself be happy, no matter the injustice in this world.   You can’t maintain a positive outlook on life if all you surround yourself with is negative people.  A man I like to call a friend, Matthew Ebel, elaborated in his blog about &lt;a href=&quot;http://matthewebel.com/2014/06/25/the-economics-of-pooping-on-your-friends/&quot;&gt;pooping on your friends.&lt;/a&gt;  Matt’s a bit more scatological (see what I did there), but he makes a great point.  You can’t keep doing that.   If you’re around negative people, or negative events, surprise, you’re going to be a negative person.  And then you’ll be sucking life out of things.  You’ll wake up and wonder what the fuck happened. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s where I’m at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feeding-the-right-wolf&quot;&gt;Feeding the right wolf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you feed the right wolf?  How do you stop the negativity?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it’s a matter of focusing on what I like.  I like coding.  I like making friends. I like writing.  I like working out and getting fit and cooking.  I don’t like fighting on twitter, or IRC, or tumblr, or furaffinity or other such places.  My good wolves and bad wolves become very obvious when I think about what brings me joy versus what brings me discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;: I’m going to start unfollowing or muting negative people.  It’s nothing personal, but it really is a matter of feeding the good wolves.  It’s a matter of finding people who bring challenges and fun and excitement to my life.  Those are the people I want to be with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coding&lt;/em&gt;:  For coding, I’m going to focus on 365 commits.  Starting july 1, I’m going to involve myself in at least 365 different commits here on Github.  It can be my own projects, it can be other projects, it can be anything.  But it has to be something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writing&lt;/em&gt;:  Some of the coding will probably be centered around an interactive fiction game/story.  So that will feed that wolf that likes writing.   I also plan on involving myself more with the various fandoms that I love, and the writing community there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Coding, part two&lt;/em&gt;:  I’m a professional coder.  I’m a member of a very high intensity tiger team.   We get amazing things done, and have learned plenty of things.  I should be presenting this stuff.  I should be going to various conferences.  I want to get a job at a major player in the industry, and I didn’t even realize I’m AT a major player in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cooking&lt;/em&gt;: I enjoy a number of the things I’ve cooked in this paleo diet lifestyle.  I stopped because it became too much work, but the reality is that I spend a lot of time feeding that stupid negative wolf that could probably be better spent making my life actually better.  Instead of hashtagging some cause, I could be out there making things better.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fitness&lt;/em&gt;: Right now, I’m writing this after a workout.  I like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.crossfit.com&quot;&gt;Crossfit&lt;/a&gt;, and I need to do it more.  If anything, it’s an exceptional stress release.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gaming&lt;/em&gt;: Hey, Games are fun, and I plan on playing them :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-wont-be-doing&quot;&gt;What I won’t be doing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t be engaging in arguments on twitter anymore.  I won’t be following people who don’t have good things to say or good things to share.  If all you’re doing is retweeting things that make you angry, what are you doing to your friends?  What are you saying about your life to your friends?  I want to hear about what awesome things you’re doing, not about how angry you are.  In fact, I won’t be putting up with arguing on line anymore if it has no value.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m not saying some arguments don’t have value.  Some things DO need to be discussed.  Some things DO need to be debated.  But I would definitely argue (hah) that there is no possible way Twitter will &lt;em&gt;EVER&lt;/em&gt; be a good forum for it.  It simply won’t.  Complex thoughts need more than 140 characters to articulate, and simple thoughts aren’t really worth arguing over.  That said, most things REALLY don’t affect me, and I probably won’t be arguing those things either.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finale&quot;&gt;Finale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s that.  That’s what stands in front of me.  That’s what I woke up tired of seeing in me.  That’s what needs to be reinvented.  And for you?  Which wolf will you feed?  If you looked in the mirror today and wondered what the hell happened to the happy you, I think you need to seriously consider what you want out of life, and if your actions are getting you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go get’m.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 16:16:18 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://graemelion.github.io/life/reinvention/me/2014/06/25/reinvention/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://graemelion.github.io/life/reinvention/me/2014/06/25/reinvention/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
